<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>neurips | Jonathan K. Kummerfeld</title>
    <link>https://www.jkk.name/tag/neurips/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.jkk.name/tag/neurips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>neurips</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 Jonathan K. Kummerfeld</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 13:00:23 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.jkk.name/images/icon_hua0d6326cebee282657b97e45398e76a5_17367_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>neurips</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/tag/neurips/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>No-Press Diplomacy: Modeling Multi-Agent Gameplay (Paquette et al., 2019)</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/post/2019-09-13_diplomacynopress/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 13:00:23 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/post/2019-09-13_diplomacynopress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Games have been a focus of AI research for decades, from Samuel&amp;rsquo;s checkers program in the 1950s, to Deep Blue playing Chess in the 1990s, and AlphaGo playing Go in the 2010s.
All of those are two-player sequential games.
In this paper (to appear at NeurIPS), we looked at Diplomacy, a seven player game with simultaneous turns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper makes three main contributions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A neural model that plays the game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software to play the game (determining the outcomes of player actions is a non-trivial problem).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experiments with supervised learning and reinforcement learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our paper only considers the version of the game where players can not talk to each other (No Press).
Engaging in conversation in the game is a fascinating challenge that will involve a lot more work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How well does the bot play the game?
It convincingly beats prior systems designed for the game.
Playing against it, I saw an impressive improvement over the course of the project.
Early on I won trivially with mostly conservative moves.
Later I had to carefully consider my moves, and was unable to win as certain powers (e.g. Austria).
Eventually I was unable to beat the bot without playing several times, using observations from one game to inform my strategy in subsequent games.
I am not an expert player, but I doubt a human playing one power in the game with no prior knowledge can win against the bot.
However, I think a single bot playing against six skilled humans would almost definitely lose (we did not test this setting).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1909.02128&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{neurips19diplomacy,
  author    = {Paquette, Philip and Lu, Yuchen and Bocco, Steven and Smith, Max O. and Ortiz-Gagn{\&#39;e}, Satya and Kummerfeld, Jonathan K. and Pineau, Joelle and Singh, Satinder and Courville, Aaron},
  title     = {No-Press Diplomacy: Modeling Multi-Agent Gameplay},
  booktitle = {Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 32},
  year      = {2019},
  month     = {December},
  pages     = {},
  url       = {},
  arxiv     = {https://arxiv.org/abs/1909.02128},
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
