<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>acl | Jonathan K. Kummerfeld</title>
    <link>https://www.jkk.name/tag/acl/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.jkk.name/tag/acl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>acl</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Jonathan K. Kummerfeld</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 11:19:06 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.jkk.name/images/icon_hua0d6326cebee282657b97e45398e76a5_17367_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>acl</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/tag/acl/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Large-Scale Corpus for Conversation Disentanglement (Kummerfeld et al., 2019)</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/post/2019-07-10_disentanglement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 11:19:06 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/post/2019-07-10_disentanglement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is about my own paper to appear at ACL later this month.
What is interesting about this paper will depend on your research interests, so that&amp;rsquo;s how I&amp;rsquo;ve broken down this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few key points first:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://jkk.name/irc-disentanglement/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Data and code&lt;/a&gt; are available on Github.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jkkummerfeld/irc-disentanglement/raw/master/acl19irc.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; is also available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The general-purpose span labeling and linking 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://jkk.name/slate/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;annotation tool&lt;/a&gt; we used is also appearing at ACL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check out 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dstc8-track2/NOESIS-II&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DSTC 8 Track 2&lt;/a&gt;, which is based on this work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;you-study-discourse&#34;&gt;You study discourse&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We investigated discourse structure when multiple conversations are occurring in the same stream of communication.
In our case, the stream is a technical support channel for Ubuntu on Internet Relay Chat (IRC).
We annotated each message with which message(s) it was a response to.
As far as we are aware, this is the first large-scale corpus with this kind of discourse structure in synchronous chat.
Here is an example from the data, with annotations marked by edges and colours:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.jkk.name/img/post/irc-disentanglement-example.png&#34; alt=&#34;IRC Disentanglement Example&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t frame the paper as being about reply-structure though.
Instead, we focus on a byproduct of these annotations - conversation disentanglement.
Given our graph of reply-structure, each connected component is a single conversation (as shown by each colour in the example).
The key prior work on the disentanglement problem is 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aclweb.org/anthology/P08-1095&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Elsner and Charniak (2008)&lt;/a&gt;, who released the largest annotated resource for the task, with 2,500 messages manually separated into conversations.
We annotated their data with our annotation scheme and 75,000 additional messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We built a set of simple models for predicting reply-structure and did some analysis of assumptions about discourse from prior disentanglement work, but there is certainly more scope for study here.
One direction would be to develop better models for this task.
Another would be to study patterns in the data to understand how people are able to follow the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;you-work-on-dialogue&#34;&gt;You work on dialogue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been a lot of work recently using the Ubuntu dataset from 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rkadlec/ubuntu-ranking-dataset-creator&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lowe et al., (2015)&lt;/a&gt;, which was produced by heuristically disentangling conversations from the same IRC channel we use.
Their work opened up a fantastic research opportunity by providing 930,000 conversations for training and evaluating dialogue systems.
However, they were unable to evaluate the quality of their conversations because they had no annotated data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using our data, we found that only 20% of their conversations are a true prefix of a conversation (since their next utterance classification task cuts the conversation off part-way, being a true prefix is all that matters).
Many conversations are missing messages, and some have extra messages from other conversations.
Unsurprisingly, our trained model does better, producing conversations that are a true prefix 81% of the time.
We also noticed that their heuristic was incorrectly linking messages far apart in time.
This is not tested by our evaluation set, so we constructed this figure, which shows the problem is quite common:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.jkk.name/img/post/irc-disentanglement-comparison.png&#34; alt=&#34;IRC Disentanglement Comparison&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purple results are based on the output of our model over the entire Ubuntu IRC logs.
That output is the basis of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dstc8-track2/NOESIS-II&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DSTC 8 Track 2&lt;/a&gt;.
Once the competition finishes (October 20th, 2019) we will release all of the conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;you-am-interested-in-studying-online-communities&#34;&gt;You am interested in studying online communities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not my area of expertise, but our data and models could enable the exploration of interesting questions.
For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the structure of the community? By looking at who asks for help and who responds we could see patterns of behaviour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does a community evolve over time? This data spans 15 years, during which there were many Ubuntu releases, Stackoverflow was created, other Ubuntu forums were created, etc. It seems likely that those events and more would be reflected in the data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be interesting to apply the model to other communities, but that would require additional in-domain data to get good results.
We have no plans to collect additional data at this stage, and for other channels there are copyright questions that might be difficult to resolve (the Ubuntu channels have an open access license).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;you-mainly-care-about-neural-network-architectures&#34;&gt;You mainly care about neural network architectures&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We experimented with a bunch of ideas that didn&amp;rsquo;t improve performance, so our final model is very simple (a feedforward network with features representing the logs and sentences represented by averaging and max-pooling GloVe embeddings).
Maybe that means there is an opportunity for you to improve on our results with a fancy model?
One of our motivations for making such a large new resource was to make it possible to train sophisticated models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;acknowledgments&#34;&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project has been going since I started at Michigan as a postdoc funded by a grant from IBM.
The final paper is the result of collaboration with a large group of people from Michigan and IBM.
Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jkkummerfeld/irc-disentanglement/raw/master/acl19irc.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{acl19disentangle,
  author    = {Kummerfeld, Jonathan K. and Gouravajhala, Sai R. and Peper, Joseph and Athreya, Vignesh and Gunasekara, Chulaka and Ganhotra, Jatin and Patel, Siva Sankalp and Polymenakos, Lazaros and Lasecki, Walter S.},
  title     = {A Large-Scale Corpus for Conversation Disentanglement},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 57th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers)},
  location  = {Florence, Italy},
  month     = {July},
  year      = {2019},
  url       = {https://github.com/jkkummerfeld/irc-disentanglement/raw/master/acl19irc.pdf},
  arxiv     = {https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.11118},
  software  = {https://jkk.name/irc-disentanglement},
  data      = {https://jkk.name/irc-disentanglement},
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning the Curriculum with Bayesian Optimization for Task-Specific Word Representation Learning (Tsvetkov et al., 2016)</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/post/2018-03-05_curriculum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 21:09:58 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/post/2018-03-05_curriculum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Usually when we learn, we have a curriculum designed to incrementally build understanding.
It seems reasonable that the same idea could be useful for machine learning, and indeed there is a large body of work on the topic.
This paper explores the specific question of whether a curriculum can help develop task-specific word vectors, and whether we can determine an effective curriculum automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They define a linear model with a range of features that characterise a paragraph of text, such as the number of distinct words, the number of prepositional phrases, and the average number of syllables per word.
Paragraphs are sorted by the model and used to train word vectors with word2vec.
These word vectors are then used as part of a model for a target task, giving a score that indicates the quality of the curriculum.
Based on this score the weights for the model are updated, using a form of Bayesian optimisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One really nice aspect of this paper is the range of tasks considered: sentiment analysis, NER, POS tagging, and parsing.
Learning a curriculum does improve performance slightly, and which features are important varies across the tasks (indicating the importance of task-specific curriculums).
However, the models are somewhat restricted (as shown by the low absolute performance) because they do not change the word vectors during training.
For most of this paper that&amp;rsquo;s a reasonable decision, as it allows a clearer learning signal, but it would have been interesting to also see the impact on the normal training scenario and a state-of-the-art model.
In my experience (and in our soon-to-appear NAACL paper) we find that variations in word vectors can disappear during training for a downstream task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/P16-1013&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{tsvetkov-EtAl:2016:P16-1,
  author    = {Tsvetkov, Yulia  and  Faruqui, Manaal  and  Ling, Wang  and  MacWhinney, Brian  and  Dyer, Chris},
  title     = {Learning the Curriculum with Bayesian Optimization for Task-Specific Word Representation Learning},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers)},
  month     = {August},
  year      = {2016},
  address   = {Berlin, Germany},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {130--139},
  url       = {http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/P16-1013}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Semantic Parsing over Multiple Knowledge-bases (Herzig et al., 2017)</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-12-05_multidomainparsing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 19:28:33 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-12-05_multidomainparsing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One reason learning for semantic parsing is difficult is that the datasets are generally small.
Assuming some words behave similarly across domains, multi-domain parsing should improve performance by providing more data, which is essentially what this paper finds.
They consider several configurations, all based on a sequence to sequence LSTM:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Train a separate model for every domain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a single model. They do three subtypes here, (a) that&amp;rsquo;s it, (b) add an LSTM input at each step with the domain, (c) give the domain as a token at the start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a single encoder model, but a different decoder for each domain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combine (1) and (3), have two encoders, one that is domain specific and one that is trained on all domains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results show that any of these does better than (1), with (2b) doing best.
There also seems to be three sections: first the independent models (1), then the models with multiple decoders (3 and 4), then the variants of (2).
A natural thing to try would be a version of (4) with a single decoder, in which case the thing that is shared is the output space representation (rather than the input space as the motivation for the paper frames it).
From the paper it sounds like very little hyperparameter tuning was tried, which is a shame because it makes it less clear how definitive the results are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-2098&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{herzig-berant:2017:Short,
  author    = {Herzig, Jonathan  and  Berant, Jonathan},
  title     = {Neural Semantic Parsing over Multiple Knowledge-bases},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 2: Short Papers)},
  month     = {July},
  year      = {2017},
  address   = {Vancouver, Canada},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {623--628},
  url       = {http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-2098}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Local Detection Approach for Named Entity Recognition and Mention Detection (Xu et al., 2017)</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-12-01_nonsequencener/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 15:28:59 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-12-01_nonsequencener/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The classic NER system is a model that has a lot of curated features, like lists of people, and does inference by choosing the top scoring tag sequence for the whole sentence, using Viterbi decoding.
The neural version swaps the curated features for word vectors, and viterbi inference for an LSTM (maybe with beam search).
This paper makes the argument that in reality people are very good at identifying an entity in isolation, so why do global decoding for the best tag sequence?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that perspective, they make a model that scores every span of the sentence independently using a feedforward network.
To get an input representing context, they use a weighted sum of word embeddings, where the weights decay exponentially further from the span (FOFE = Fixed-size Ordinally Forgetting Encoding).
The authors point out that this gives a fixed length encoding that could be reversed to recover the original sequence (assuming arbitrary precision floating point numbers).
Thinking about the calculation though, a word ten positions away is having its vector scaled down by a factor of a thousand, so it probably has negligible impact on the decision.
They also apply this idea to the characters of the span itself in both directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One tradeoff with the independent classification idea is that it can select overlapping spans.
This is a benefit in one sense, because it naturally handles nested entities (e.g. &amp;ldquo;[Member of the Order of [Australia]]&amp;quot;), but for partially overlapping spans we have to decide which to keep.
Their solution is to sort by model score and keep the higher scoring option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The experiments show this is comparable with previous work using LSTMs.
There were a few things I found interesting in the results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The FOFE encoding for characters is far worse than a CNN encoding when on their own, but give similar gains when combined with word level features. Since the FOFE essentially ignores the centre of long spans, this suggests they are both learning some representation of prefixes and suffixes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They don&amp;rsquo;t try it, but this model seems very amenable to gazetteers, which may be a way to further boost performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They have an in-house dataset of 10,000 manually labeled documents (!), but it only gives a 3% gain on the KBP evaluation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-1114&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{xu-jiang-watcharawittayakul:2017:Long,
  author    = {Xu, Mingbin  and  Jiang, Hui  and  Watcharawittayakul, Sedtawut},
  title     = {A Local Detection Approach for Named Entity Recognition and Mention Detection},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers)},
  month     = {July},
  year      = {2017},
  address   = {Vancouver, Canada},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {1237--1247},
  url       = {http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-1114}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint Extraction of Entities and Relations Based on a Novel Tagging Scheme (Zheng et al., 2017)</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-30_taggingrelations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 20:01:41 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-30_taggingrelations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper considers the task of identifying named entities in a sentence and the relations between them.
The contribution is a way of formulating the task as tagging, so a bi-directional LSTM can be applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tags are like in NER (Begin, Inside, End, Single, Outside), but rather than Person, Location, etc, they label each entity with the relation it is participating in, and whether it is in role one or two for the relation.
Applying a two layer bidirectional LSTM to this set up gets to state-of-the-art precision on news data.
To get SotA F-score they modify the loss to place less weight on Outside tags, which raises recall at the cost of precision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One catch with this approach is handling multiple relations of the same type.
The solution here is to link pairs that are closest together (unclear what they do for nesting).
That doesn&amp;rsquo;t handle overlapping relations, which the authors say is particularly common in the BioInfer data (I&amp;rsquo;m curious how much it is hurting here too).
It&amp;rsquo;s unclear how this could be addressed without a radical redesign, since extending the tag scheme could lead to sparsity issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was not familiar with this data, so I looked back to the original paper the annotated test data came from: 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/P11-1055&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hoffman et al., (2011)&lt;/a&gt;.
There is no dev set, only a 395 sentence test set, so the standard practise is to use random 10% samples of the test data for development.
Also, if I understand it correctly, the data was annotated by manually confirming the output of systems, which means it will have recall errors.
If interest in this data grows, going back and annotating more seems worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-1113&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{zheng-EtAl:2017:Long,
  author    = {Zheng, Suncong  and  Wang, Feng  and  Bao, Hongyun  and  Hao, Yuexing  and  Zhou, Peng  and  Xu, Bo},
  title     = {Joint Extraction of Entities and Relations Based on a Novel Tagging Scheme},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers)},
  month     = {July},
  year      = {2017},
  address   = {Vancouver, Canada},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {1227--1236},
  url       = {http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-1113}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstractive Document Summarization with a Graph-Based Attentional Neural Model (Tan et al., 2017)</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-29_abstractivesummarisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 19:14:05 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-29_abstractivesummarisation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most effective summarisation systems are extractive, selecting the most important sentences in a document and sticking them together.
Clearly that is not how people write summaries, but creating abstractive summaries means generating fluent language.
At the same time, most datasets are based on news text, where the first few sentences are a strong baseline summary (by design, as journalists need to assume that the reader could stop at any point).
This paper introduces several ideas to get state-of-the-art results on summarisation using an abstractive system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three core new ideas, one for decoding and two for the model.
The idea in decoding is a beam search in which the score is increased when adding bigrams that occur in the source but are not in the output.
In the model, they propose a new form of attention based on PageRank, similar to previous methods used for ranking sentences in summarisation.
For every pair of sentences plus the current decoder hidden vector, a similarity score is calculated ($h_1 M h_2$), where $M$ is a matrix of parameters.
This produces a matrix of similarities, which they run PageRank on with initialisation set so that all weight starts on the decoder hidden vector.
That produces a score for each input sentence, which is normalised to get attention values.
The second idea is that they don&amp;rsquo;t want to attend to the same sentence multiple times, so before normalising they subtract the previous score for that sentence (with it capped at 0 to avoid negative values).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, these lead to state of the art results, beating both extractive and abstractive systems.
Though in human evaluation using the first three sentences as a summary remains a very strong baseline, only slightly behind this system on informativeness and ahead on coherence and fluency.
Ablation shows that the decoding idea has the biggest impact, but the graph based attention does help.
Interestingly, if the score in decoding is extremely biased to focus on the bigram addition aspect performance only decreases a little.
That may reflect the nature of the metric, which is based on ngram overlap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also a bunch of little details that may be crucial, like adding markers for entities (which seems like a possible space for a more elegant solution).
I&amp;rsquo;m not sure the beam search scoring idea has applications beyond summarisation, but thee modified attention might!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-1108&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{tan-wan-xiao:2017:Long,
  author    = {Tan, Jiwei  and  Wan, Xiaojun  and  Xiao, Jianguo},
  title     = {Abstractive Document Summarization with a Graph-Based Attentional Neural Model},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers)},
  month     = {July},
  year      = {2017},
  address   = {Vancouver, Canada},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {1171--1181},
  url       = {http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-1108}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Error-repair Dependency Parsing for Ungrammatical Texts (Sakaguchi et al., 2017)</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-22_errorrepairparsing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 15:48:53 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-22_errorrepairparsing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This work presents a system that parses sentences and identifies grammatical errors simultaneously.
It&amp;rsquo;s an intuitive combination - a syntactic model should assign higher probability to a parse for a fixed version of a sentence than the one with a mistake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They build on an incremental &amp;lsquo;easy-first&amp;rsquo; dependency parsing approach.
Easy-First parsing starts with the set of words in the sentence and allows an edge to be created between any adjacent pair of words.
Once an edge is created, the child is hidden beneath its parent, so now the parent is effectively adjacent to a word slightly further away.
Then the process repeats, until there is only one word left (the root of the sentence).
In a way it is like following a dynamic program, but with only a single state that ties together multiple cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The change in this paper is the addition of actions that insert a word, delete a word, or alter a word.
To make it work, there are constraints to avoid cycles of repeated actions (e.g. insert-delete-insert-delete&amp;hellip;), and on the sets of allowed word substitutions.
To produce additional training data, a tool is used to inject errors into grammatical text.
On error detection, this approach does lead to improvements, though it changes a relatively small number of the sentences.
On dependency parsing it is (unsurprisingly) worse than a baseline system on grammatical text.
It does perform better on ungrammatical text, though the data is generated using the same process as the training data, creating a bias in the system&amp;rsquo;s favour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-2030&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{sakaguchi-post-vandurme:2017:Short,
  author    = {Sakaguchi, Keisuke  and  Post, Matt  and  Van Durme, Benjamin},
  title     = {Error-repair Dependency Parsing for Ungrammatical Texts},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 2: Short Papers)},
  month     = {July},
  year      = {2017},
  address   = {Vancouver, Canada},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {189--195},
  url       = {http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-2030}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attention Strategies for Multi-Source Sequence-to-Sequence Learning (Libovicky et al., 2017)</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-21_multiinputattention/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 16:42:19 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-21_multiinputattention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Attention, a weighted average over vectors with weights determined based on context (usually decoder state), has proven effective in many NLP tasks.
There are several variants, and this paper adds new types that address the question of how to apply attention to different sources at the same time, such as text and an image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They consider three general versions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concatenation, just do attention separately then concatenate the vectors from the input sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flat, do the weighted average over all of the inputs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hierarchical, do attention separately, but then combine the vectors with another phase of attention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also explore two variations that are orthogonal to the list above:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first step and the last step in attention both involve the input vectors being multiplied by a weight matrix. Should that matrix be shared for the two steps, or different? (the first informs the decision of what to give high weight in the average, the second determines what is being averaged over)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;sentinel gates&lt;/em&gt;, a modification to the way the inputs and context vector are combined that allow one or the other to be ignored.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They consider two tasks, (1) translation when both an image and source sentence are given, (2) post-editing a translated sentence with the original source given.
The results show fairly clear trends, though the systems are not great compared to baselines (worse than a text only baseline for the first, and only slightly better than a direct MT system for the second).
The trends are that hierarchical is best, the sentinel doesn&amp;rsquo;t help, and it is better to not share weights (though I wonder if that would be true when controlling for the total number of parameters).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-2031&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{libovicky-helcl:2017:Short,
  author    = {Libovick\&#39;{y}, Jind\v{r}ich  and  Helcl, Jind\v{r}ich},
  title     = {Attention Strategies for Multi-Source Sequence-to-Sequence Learning},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 2: Short Papers)},
  month     = {July},
  year      = {2017},
  address   = {Vancouver, Canada},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {196--202},
  url       = {http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-2031}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robust Incremental Neural Semantic Graph Parsing (Buys et al., 2017)</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-20_mrsparser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 10:13:12 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-20_mrsparser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-16_ucca/&#34;&gt;UCCA parser&lt;/a&gt;, this paper explores a transition-based neural model for semantic parsing, but for Minimal Recursion Semantics instead of Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation.
Comparing MRS and UCCA, every word gets a non-terminal symbol in MRS, plus additional non-terminals for phenomena like quantification, while UCCA only introduces them for special cases like linking to a coordination.
Both have discontinuous graph structures, creating a challenge for most parsers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UCCA and MRS parsers extend the basic shift-reduce transitions in different ways.
Here, crossing edges can be added with a transition that forms edges between the front of the buffer and a word anywhere in the stack, while the UCCA parser used swapping and a additional reduce actions for graph edges.
The models are similar, both using a form of stack-RNN, but with different structures (partly as a result of the different transition schemes).
The results in this case are not state-of-the-art, though this task has received more attention, and the data is slightly biased (the parser that does better, ACE, is based on the grammar that was used to determine which sentences to include).
However, the system can also be applied to AMR, and does fairly well, better than other neural AMR parsers at the time (and more recent ideas for improvements are large orthogonal).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-1112&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{buys-blunsom:2017:Long,
  author    = {Buys, Jan  and  Blunsom, Phil},
  title     = {Robust Incremental Neural Semantic Graph Parsing},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers)},
  month     = {July},
  year      = {2017},
  address   = {Vancouver, Canada},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {1215--1226},
  url       = {http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-1112}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Two-Stage Parsing Method for Text-Level Discourse Analysis (Wang et al., 2017)</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-17_twostagediscourseparsing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 18:40:20 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-17_twostagediscourseparsing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discourse parsing for Rhetorical Structure Theory is difficult partly because it involves a range of relation types at different scales (within and between sentences) and partly because there is relatively little annotated data available.
To deal with the limited data, this paper breaks the task into two parts: (1) identify relations, (2) assign labels.
Their system is state-of-the-art, and an ablation shows that the division of tasks helps performance.
They also divide up the labeling step to have different classifiers for within sentences, between sentences in the same paragraph, and between paragraphs, which also helps a little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find the second improvement surprising, since an expanded feature set for a single classifier would be able to emulate their multi-classifier model, while having the advantage of sharing information between classes.
The first improvement is more intuitive (a denser space makes for an easier problem), though I wonder whether this will be one point on the back-and-forth that usually occurs between sequential and joint models (with joint models usually winning in the end).
This paper also continues the trend of transition-based inference applying effectively to tasks, which makes sense if our models are getting good enough that search errors are not a major issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-2029&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{wang-li-wang:2017:Short,
  author    = {Wang, Yizhong  and  Li, Sujian  and  Wang, Houfeng},
  title     = {A Two-Stage Parsing Method for Text-Level Discourse Analysis},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 2: Short Papers)},
  month     = {July},
  year      = {2017},
  address   = {Vancouver, Canada},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {184--188},
  url       = {http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-2029}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Transition-Based Directed Acyclic Graph Parser for UCCA (Hershcovich et al., 2017)</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-16_ucca/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 17:24:59 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-16_ucca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few years interest has risen in parsing structures other than projective trees (including my dissertation!).
There are now a range of different datasets with annotations for syntactic and/or semantic structure that include discontinuous constituents and graphs.
This paper looks at UCCA, a proposed formalism that is somewhat similar to SRL, with non-terminals included to allow for easier handling of cases like coordination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parser is a transition based, with a transition system that covers all the structural phenomena in UCCA: non-terminals, discontinuous spans, and multiple parents.
The key to consistent multiple parents is distinguishing the addition of edges that are the primary parent (to prevent multiple being added).
To get discontinuity, they use a swap operation.
They consider a range of models, including both linear and neural network examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dataset is relatively small, with only 4,268 training sentences, and the task is hard, so performance is relatively low (50 - 75 for primary edges, 20-50 for others).
The neural model consistently beats the linear ones, particularly for the non-primary edges.
Comparing to other standard parsers (retrained on this data), the ability to generate the full space of structures makes a big difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be interesting to see coverage of this data for one-endpoint crossing graphs.
If it is high, then my own parser could be applied fairly directly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-1104&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{hershcovich-abend-rappoport:2017:Long,
  author    = {Hershcovich, Daniel  and  Abend, Omri  and  Rappoport, Ari},
  title     = {A Transition-Based Directed Acyclic Graph Parser for UCCA},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers)},
  month     = {July},
  year      = {2017},
  address   = {Vancouver, Canada},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {1127--1138},
  url       = {http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-1104}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Knowledge Bases in LSTMs for Improving Machine Reading (Yang et al., 2017)</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-10_kginlstm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 15:37:15 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-10_kginlstm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Structured information sources have been effectively used for entity detection and typing in linear models with the information encoded as binary features.
This paper looks at how to integrate vector representations of structured information into an LSTM.
The solution is an additional processing step during output generation, in which the vectors for relevant entities in the structured data are combined with the standard LSTM output (note, they do not affect the cell itself, so the information is not passed on through the recurrence).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case the structured information is a set of tuples forming a graph of relations between entities, from either NELL or WordNet.
The actual encoding of entities is an application of prior work; vectors representing tuples are trained with the objective that the score for any tuple is higher than made-up tuples (where the score is $v_a M_r v_b$ for entities $a$ and $b$ in relation $r$).
The set of relevant entities for a particular word in the sentence is obtained by string matching, and then attention is used to combine them.
There is also a kind of gating mechanism to choose how big a role the entities play in the prediction, using a combination of the input, hidden state, and cell state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results are interesting not only because this method helps, but because of how well the standard LSTM does on this task, matching or exceeding prior results.
This is even more impressive given how small ACE is (if I remember correctly).
The other key observations are that having a sequence level loss (using a CRF) helps, and NELL and WordNet seem to be providing different types of information (as using both leads to further improvements).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-1132&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{yang-mitchell:2017:Long,
  author    = {Yang, Bishan  and  Mitchell, Tom},
  title     = {Leveraging Knowledge Bases in LSTMs for Improving Machine Reading},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers)},
  month     = {July},
  year      = {2017},
  address   = {Vancouver, Canada},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {1436--1446},
  url       = {http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-1132}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Symmetric Collaborative Dialogue Agents with Dynamic Knowledge Graph Embeddings (He et al., 2017)</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-08_graphdialogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 18:46:04 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-08_graphdialogue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Task-oriented dialogue systems are often focused on a very narrow task, to the point where the state can be described completely with a tuple (e.g. preferences for a restaurant).
This paper sets up a more challenging task with more complex language use, while still having a specific goal and directly relevant structured information.
They collected 11,000 dialogues, where two people have private lists of friends and are trying to identify which friend they have in common.
While this is a lot of data, the mechanical turk workers are clearly moving fast, with dialogues taking 1.5 minutes on average, and in 18% of cases they get the friend wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The algorithmic contribution is that the lists of people are represented as a graph, where nodes are properties like company and hobby.
The graph is used to generate vectors for each person by running a form of message passing over its structure.
During generation, the LSTM uses attention over these vectors to inform the output choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few interesting things in the output:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are cases where the output is incorrect, as in, says a fact about the structured information / knowledge base that is false.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluation is tricky, and over the metrics they consider sometimes this wins, but sometimes the baseline system (rules) does better. In particular, success on bot-bot evaluation doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to clearly transfer to bot-human experiments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The utterances are very fluent, but that may be because it&amp;rsquo;s essentially copying from the training data. It looks like there is diversity in the dataset, but a lot of utterances do fit a template of &amp;ldquo;I have X who Y&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-1162&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{he-EtAl:2017:Long4,
  author    = {He, He  and  Balakrishnan, Anusha  and  Eric, Mihail  and  Liang, Percy},
  title     = {Learning Symmetric Collaborative Dialogue Agents with Dynamic Knowledge Graph Embeddings},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers)},
  month     = {July},
  year      = {2017},
  address   = {Vancouver, Canada},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {1766--1776},
  abstract  = {We study a \emph{symmetric collaborative dialogue} setting
	in which two agents, each with private knowledge,
	must strategically communicate to achieve a common goal.
	The open-ended dialogue state in this setting poses new challenges for existing
	dialogue systems.
	We collected a dataset of 11K human-human dialogues,
	which exhibits interesting lexical, semantic, and strategic elements.
	To model
	both structured knowledge and unstructured language,
	we propose a neural model with dynamic knowledge graph embeddings
	that evolve as the dialogue progresses.
	Automatic and human evaluations show that our model is both more effective
	at achieving the goal and more human-like than baseline neural and rule-based
	models.},
  url       = {http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-1162}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint Modeling of Content and Discourse Relations in Dialogues (Qin et al., 2017)</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-03_discourserelations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 15:40:32 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-03_discourserelations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Automatically generating high quality meeting notes and summaries would be awesome, but involves solving many challenges.
Here, they assume speech recognition is already done and we also know the structure over utterances indicating which previous utterance each is a response to.
The task is to label each of those utterance-utterance pairs with a type (e.g. elaboration) and to select the key phrase of each utterance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two datasets are used, the AMI and ICSO meeting corpora, which have all of the required information.
The new idea here is to jointly model the choice of link label and the key phrase, which is intuitive.
To show the value of joint modeling they run a version of the system with the same linear model, but with independent inference, which performs quite a bit worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One neat follow up is that by combining the key phrases into a list you get a form of summary.
According to automatic metrics it is quite a bit better than running the summarisation system they compare to, though it&amp;rsquo;s still a long way from a human summary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-1090&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{qin-wang-kim:2017:Long,
  author    = {Qin, Kechen  and  Wang, Lu  and  Kim, Joseph},
  title     = {Joint Modeling of Content and Discourse Relations in Dialogues},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers)},
  month     = {July},
  year      = {2017},
  address   = {Vancouver, Canada},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {974--984},
  url       = {http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-1090}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting annotation noise in automatically labelled data (Rehbein and Ruppenhofer, ACL 2017)</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-10-13_errordetection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 13:32:19 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-10-13_errordetection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Active learning doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to get much attention in NLP, probably because of fear that developing data based on the errors of one model will introduce a particular sampling bias.
This paper is a nice example of a problem it can be applied to that doesn&amp;rsquo;t raise that issue: detecting all the errors in a system&amp;rsquo;s output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scenario is that you have a bunch of models for doing a task (e.g. POS tagging) and a new dataset with no labeled data, which you would like to label.
Having a person label the data would take a long time and doesn&amp;rsquo;t take advantage of these systems.
At the same time, we can&amp;rsquo;t just run the systems and use their output because they aren&amp;rsquo;t perfect, particularly out of domain.
We could run the systems and check their output, which could be faster than annotating directly, but would still take a long time.
If we don&amp;rsquo;t mind having some errors, we can check just some output, but how do we decide what to check?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper applies the generative model from 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/N13-1132&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MACE&lt;/a&gt; to build a generative model of system outputs.
The model is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For each example, sample the true label with a uniform prior&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then, for each classifier, sample from a Bernoulli distribution to decide if they are good or not&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A good classifier returns the true label, a not good classifier samples from a multinomial over the options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we don&amp;rsquo;t know the parameters of the model, or the true labels, use expectation maximisation to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work takes that model, trains it and uses it to identify the sample that is most uncertain.
A person annotates it, the correct label replaces one of the system predictions, and EM is run again.
This is repeated until either there appear to be no more errors, or annotators run out of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How well does it work?
The main metric is precision: how many of the instances asked for annotation actually have errors.
For POS tagging on WSJ text, the taggers initially get 2.5% of words wrong.
To get that down to 1.1% the precision is 33%, and to get it to 0.65% precision is 17.6%.
On an out of domain dataset, the error rate is 10% initially, and is down to 5% with a precision of 50%.
Put differently, in a dataset of 25,000 tokens, with 2,500 errors, after checking 2,500 tokens, there are only 1,250 errors (another 2,500 checks brings it down to 730).
It also works well for NER, and consistently does better than the alternative they compare to (consider the taggers a committee and find the examples with highest entropy, i.e. greatest disagreement).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems like a natural fit for 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://prodi.gy/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;prodigy&lt;/a&gt; and something that could be broadly useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aclweb.org/anthology/P/P17/P17-1107.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{rehbein-ruppenhofer:2017:Long,
  author    = {Rehbein, Ines  and  Ruppenhofer, Josef},
  title     = {Detecting annotation noise in automatically labelled data},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers)},
  month     = {July},
  year      = {2017},
  address   = {Vancouver, Canada},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {1160--1170},
  url       = {http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-1107}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search-based Neural Structured Learning for Sequential Question Answering (Iyyer et al., ACL 2017)</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-10-10_seqqa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 13:43:36 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-10-10_seqqa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Semantic parsing datasets generally consist of (question, answer) pairs, where each pair is completely independent of the rest (one exception is ATIS, which has multi-turn conversations, though most work doesn&amp;rsquo;t use them).
In reality, we often ask a series of simple questions that together form a complex one, for example &amp;ldquo;What flights are available from Detroit to Sydney? And how much is the price if I don&amp;rsquo;t want to leave before 8am?&amp;rdquo;
This work explores these kinds of sequential questions with a new dataset and algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dataset was formed by asking crowd workers to rephrase questions from the WikiTableQuestions dataset into sequences of shorter questions.
This naturally constrains the types of questions (in particular, they reference a single table only), but covers a range of domains.
With 6,066 question sequences, and on average 2.9 questions / sequence, it&amp;rsquo;s a large dataset by semantic parsing standards.
However, there are no logical forms, only the row, column, or cell(s) that contain the answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve the problem, they treat it as choosing a sequence of actions, where each action generate a part of the execution instructions.
The model follows the recent approach of considering the contents of the database as part of the calculation (e.g. by taking the dot product of the vector for a cell and the vector for the question).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system has consistently better performance than other QA systems on the new dataset (though no results are shown for the WikiTableQuestions dataset).
At only 12.8% of sequences completely correct, there is plenty of scope for improvement.
Based on the description of the operators there are definitely additional abilities that would be useful, so this model has potential to improve.
That said, it seems difficult to generalise the model to handle more complicated databases with multiple interconnected tables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://aclweb.org/anthology/P/P17/P17-1167.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{iyyer-yih-chang:2017:Long,
  author    = {Iyyer, Mohit  and  Yih, Wen-tau  and  Chang, Ming-Wei},
  title     = {Search-based Neural Structured Learning for Sequential Question Answering},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers)},
  month     = {July},
  year      = {2017},
  address   = {Vancouver, Canada},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {1821--1831},
  url       = {http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-1167}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
