<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Advice on Jonathan K. Kummerfeld</title>
    <link>https://www.jkk.name/advice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Advice on Jonathan K. Kummerfeld</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://www.jkk.name/advice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Academic Posters</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/advice/posters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/advice/posters/</guid>
      <description>Your poster should be optimised for the following conference experience:&#xA;A person walks past your poster and sees enough from a distance to get the key idea. The person decides to either (a) keep walking, or (b) learn more. If they choose (b), there are figures on the poster you can use to explain your work. Optimising for this has a few implications:&#xA;Have a short (5-20 word) explanation in a large font that communicates the key idea.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Email Clients</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/advice/email/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/advice/email/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a happy Gmail user, but my university email address cannot be accessed from Gmail (I cannot create an application specific password and Gmail does not support OAuth2). I found the browser UI for Outlook frustrating, so I went in search of another email client.&#xA;I looked at and tried a wide range of clients. Below are my notes about what I liked / did not like about each one. Of course, these reflect my preferences.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USyd CS People</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/advice/usyd-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/advice/usyd-people/</guid>
      <description>Artificial Intelligence Nasim Ahmed Ali Anaissi Wei Bao Michael Cahill Weidong (Tom) Cai Runnan Chen Sue Chng Vera Chung Joseph Davis Hazem El-Alfy Michael Harre Maryam Khanian Jinman Kim Irena Koprinska Jonathan K. Kummerfeld Tongliang Liu Mohammad Polash Josiah Poon Simon Poon Mikhail Prokopenko Fabio Ramos Suranga Seneviratne John Stavrakakis Masa Takatsuka Kanchana Thilakarathna Nguyen Tran Xiuying Wang Zhiyong Wang Chang Xu Kalina Yacef Yu Yao Liyi Zhou Ying Zhou Albert Zomaya Complex Systems Michael Harre Joseph Lizier Mahendra Piraveenan Mikhail Prokopenko Computer Architecture, Operating Systems, Networking, and Distributed Computing Nasim Ahmed Wei Bao Athman Bouguettaya Michael Cahill Vincent Gramoli Wei Li Uwe Roehm Bernhard Scholz Shuaiwen Song John Stavrakakis Kanchana Thilakarathna Nguyen Tran Jiangshan Yu Bing Zhou Liyi Zhou Albert Zomaya Databases and Information Systems Michael Cahill Lijun Chang Joseph Davis Alan Fekete Vincent Gramoli Mohammad Polash Uwe Roehm Ying Zhou Education David Lowe Mohammad Polash John Stavrakakis Masa Takatsuka Xi Wu Kalina Yacef Graphics and Visualisation Weidong (Tom) Cai Peter Eades Vincent Gramoli Seok-Hee Hong John Stavrakakis Zhiyong Wang Anusha Withana Human-Computer Interaction Nasim Ahmed Judy Kay Maryam Khanian Bob Kummerfeld Zhanna Sarsenbayeva Eduardo Velloso Anusha Withana Kalina Yacef Programming Languages and Formal Methods Rahul Gopinath Xi Wu Liyi Zhou Security Nasim Ahmed Ahmad Azab Rahul Gopinath Vincent Gramoli Suranga Seneviratne Qiang Tang Kanchana Thilakarathna Sri AravindaKrishnan Thyagarajan Jiangshan Yu Liyi Zhou Albert Zomaya Theory Clément Canonne Lijun Chang Rahul Gopinath Vincent Gramoli Joachim Gudmundsson Julian Mestre André van Renssen Sasha Rubin Qiang Tang Sri AravindaKrishnan Thyagarajan Tony Wirth </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
