<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>syntax | Jonathan K. Kummerfeld</title>
    <link>https://www.jkk.name/tag/syntax/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.jkk.name/tag/syntax/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>syntax</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 Jonathan K. Kummerfeld</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 17:24:59 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.jkk.name/images/icon_hua0d6326cebee282657b97e45398e76a5_17367_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>syntax</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/tag/syntax/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Transition-Based Directed Acyclic Graph Parser for UCCA (Hershcovich et al., 2017)</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-16_ucca/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 17:24:59 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-16_ucca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few years interest has risen in parsing structures other than projective trees (including my dissertation!).
There are now a range of different datasets with annotations for syntactic and/or semantic structure that include discontinuous constituents and graphs.
This paper looks at UCCA, a proposed formalism that is somewhat similar to SRL, with non-terminals included to allow for easier handling of cases like coordination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parser is a transition based, with a transition system that covers all the structural phenomena in UCCA: non-terminals, discontinuous spans, and multiple parents.
The key to consistent multiple parents is distinguishing the addition of edges that are the primary parent (to prevent multiple being added).
To get discontinuity, they use a swap operation.
They consider a range of models, including both linear and neural network examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dataset is relatively small, with only 4,268 training sentences, and the task is hard, so performance is relatively low (50 - 75 for primary edges, 20-50 for others).
The neural model consistently beats the linear ones, particularly for the non-primary edges.
Comparing to other standard parsers (retrained on this data), the ability to generate the full space of structures makes a big difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be interesting to see coverage of this data for one-endpoint crossing graphs.
If it is high, then my own parser could be applied fairly directly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://aclanthology.org/P17-1104&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{hershcovich-abend-rappoport:2017:Long,
  author    = {Hershcovich, Daniel  and  Abend, Omri  and  Rappoport, Ari},
  title     = {A Transition-Based Directed Acyclic Graph Parser for UCCA},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers)},
  month     = {July},
  year      = {2017},
  address   = {Vancouver, Canada},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {1127--1138},
  url       = {https://aclanthology.org/P17-1104}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In-Order Transition-based Constituent Parsing (Liu et al., 2017)</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-14_inorderparsing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 14:10:39 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-14_inorderparsing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shift-reduce constituency parsing incrementally builds the parse either bottom-up or top-down.
The difference is whether a non-terminal is placed on the stack before or after the words that it spans.
This corresponds to two forms of depth-first traversal of the tree: pre-order or post-order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea in this paper is to do an in-order traversal, which in a binary tree means traversing the left child of a node, then the node, then its right child.
In this context that means putting the non-terminal symbol on the stack after the first word it spans, but before the rest.
The model follows the stack-LSTM approach of Dyer et al., with non-terminals always fed into the LSTM first during composition, regardless of where it was inserted into the stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This leads to a 0.5 F1 gain on standard parsing metrics, with no hyperparameter tuning.
High-level error analysis seems to show it just does better everywhere.
I wonder whether further gains could be realised with a label-sensitive ordering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.transacl.org/ojs/index.php/tacl/article/view/1199&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@article{TACL1199,
	author = {Liu, Jiangming  and Zhang, Yue },
	title = {In-Order Transition-based Constituent Parsing},
	journal = {Transactions of the Association for Computational Linguistics},
	volume = {5},
	year = {2017},
	issn = {2307-387X},
	url = {https://www.transacl.org/ojs/index.php/tacl/article/view/1199},
	pages = {413--424}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arc-Standard Spinal Parsing with Stack-LSTMs (Ballesteros et al., 2017)</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-07_spineparsinglstm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 20:42:45 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-07_spineparsinglstm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper brings together work on neural dependency parsing with the idea of non-terminal spines as a way to represent constituency structure.
Within the transition parsing inference process they can naturally fit the generation of a new spines by gradually building up the spine, which makes for a very elegant inference process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to matter what head choices are used to generate the spines (they tried leftmost word, rightmost word, and two standard schemes).
This contrasts with my own observations that the choice of head had a big impact (0.5 F) on accuracy.
I think the incrementally-built spines are the key difference.
Decisions about higher up in the spine are difficult to make when looking at a single word, but with the incremental construction there is information about a larger context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://aclanthology.org/W17-6316&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{ballesteros-carreras:2017:IWPT,
  author    = {Ballesteros, Miguel  and  Carreras, Xavier},
  title     = {Arc-Standard Spinal Parsing with Stack-LSTMs},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 15th International Conference on Parsing Technologies},
  month     = {September},
  year      = {2017},
  address   = {Pisa, Italy},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {115--121},
  url       = {https://aclanthology.org/W17-6316}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shift-Reduce Constituency Parsing with Dynamic Programming and POS Tag Lattice (Mi and Huang, 2015)</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-10-25_shiftreducedp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 14:44:13 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-10-25_shiftreducedp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper is a follow-up to yesterday&amp;rsquo;s, where the approach is implemented and evaluated on English and Chinese, with very strong results.
The novel contribution is the idea of introducing alternating steps in the dynamic program to do unary steps (not a novel idea in general, but novel in its application to the dynamic programming version of shift-reduce parsing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I found interesting here were the clear benefits of the dynamic program (DP) version.
One way of viewing this is that the DP gives a more intelligent type of beam, avoiding the issue where the beam is filled with minor variations on a theme.
Results are given for various beam sizes in both approaches, but it would be interesting to see a graph where the x-axis is number of items built.
I suspect in that situation, the gap would be smaller.
On speed, there is the nice theoretical bound of $O(n)$ for this approach, but that obscures a grammar constant related to the item structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://aclanthology.org/N15-1108&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{mi-huang:2015:NAACL-HLT,
  author    = {Mi, Haitao  and  Huang, Liang},
  title     = {Shift-Reduce Constituency Parsing with Dynamic Programming and POS Tag Lattice},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 2015 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies},
  month     = {May--June},
  year      = {2015},
  address   = {Denver, Colorado},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {1030--1035},
  url       = {https://aclanthology.org/N15-1108}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Programming Algorithms for Transition-Based Dependency Parsers (Kuhlmann et al., ACL 2011)</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-10-24_dynamictransition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 13:06:04 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/post/2017-10-24_dynamictransition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper from 2011 explores the relationship between transition based parsing and dynamic programming based parsing.
They show how to convert common dependency parsing systems (Arc-Standard and Arc-Eager) into dynamic programs, and how doing the reverse on a dynamic program gives the Arc-Hybrid approach (which has since been used in many places, and is now joined by additional systems like Arc-Swift).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benefit of this transformation is that we can find exact answers without massive beams.
The drawback is that the feature set is restricted.
This paper is theoretical, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t give a direct measure of this tradeoff, though 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://aclanthology.org/D/D13/D13-1071.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;follow up work&lt;/a&gt; shows that avoiding search errors is indeed beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all of the positive results using neural networks for multi-task learning, one thought this work leads to is whether we could treat different inference methods as different tasks.
In other words, have a single model encoding the input, then have multiple inference algorithms with different extensions of that model, all trained simultaneously.
The variation in available context for the different algorithms may force generality in the core representation shared across them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://aclanthology.org/P/P11/P11-1068.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{kuhlmann-gomezrodriguez-satta:2011:ACL-HLT2011,
  author    = {Kuhlmann, Marco  and  G\&#39;{o}mez-Rodr\&#39;{i}guez, Carlos  and  Satta, Giorgio},
  title     = {Dynamic Programming Algorithms for Transition-Based Dependency Parsers},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies},
  month     = {June},
  year      = {2011},
  address   = {Portland, Oregon, USA},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {673--682},
  url       = {https://aclanthology.org/P11-1068}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One-Endpoint Crossing Graph Parser</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/software/1ec-parsing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/software/1ec-parsing/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spine and Arc version of the Penn Treebank</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/data/shp-ptb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/data/shp-ptb/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCG to PST</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/software/ccg2pst/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/software/ccg2pst/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parse Error Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/software/parsing-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/software/parsing-analysis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive CCG Supertagging Model</title>
      <link>https://www.jkk.name/data/ccg-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jkk.name/data/ccg-model/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
