<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>semantic-parsing | Jonathan K. Kummerfeld</title>
    <link>http://www.jkk.name/tag/semantic-parsing/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://www.jkk.name/tag/semantic-parsing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>semantic-parsing</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Jonathan K. Kummerfeld</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 19:28:33 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://www.jkk.name/images/icon_hua0d6326cebee282657b97e45398e76a5_17367_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>semantic-parsing</title>
      <link>http://www.jkk.name/tag/semantic-parsing/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Semantic Parsing over Multiple Knowledge-bases (Herzig et al., 2017)</title>
      <link>http://www.jkk.name/post/2017-12-05_multidomainparsing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 19:28:33 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jkk.name/post/2017-12-05_multidomainparsing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One reason learning for semantic parsing is difficult is that the datasets are generally small.
Assuming some words behave similarly across domains, multi-domain parsing should improve performance by providing more data, which is essentially what this paper finds.
They consider several configurations, all based on a sequence to sequence LSTM:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Train a separate model for every domain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a single model. They do three subtypes here, (a) that&amp;rsquo;s it, (b) add an LSTM input at each step with the domain, (c) give the domain as a token at the start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a single encoder model, but a different decoder for each domain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combine (1) and (3), have two encoders, one that is domain specific and one that is trained on all domains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results show that any of these does better than (1), with (2b) doing best.
There also seems to be three sections: first the independent models (1), then the models with multiple decoders (3 and 4), then the variants of (2).
A natural thing to try would be a version of (4) with a single decoder, in which case the thing that is shared is the output space representation (rather than the input space as the motivation for the paper frames it).
From the paper it sounds like very little hyperparameter tuning was tried, which is a shame because it makes it less clear how definitive the results are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-2098&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{herzig-berant:2017:Short,
  author    = {Herzig, Jonathan  and  Berant, Jonathan},
  title     = {Neural Semantic Parsing over Multiple Knowledge-bases},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 2: Short Papers)},
  month     = {July},
  year      = {2017},
  address   = {Vancouver, Canada},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {623--628},
  url       = {http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-2098}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robust Incremental Neural Semantic Graph Parsing (Buys et al., 2017)</title>
      <link>http://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-20_mrsparser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 10:13:12 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-20_mrsparser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-16_ucca/&#34;&gt;UCCA parser&lt;/a&gt;, this paper explores a transition-based neural model for semantic parsing, but for Minimal Recursion Semantics instead of Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation.
Comparing MRS and UCCA, every word gets a non-terminal symbol in MRS, plus additional non-terminals for phenomena like quantification, while UCCA only introduces them for special cases like linking to a coordination.
Both have discontinuous graph structures, creating a challenge for most parsers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UCCA and MRS parsers extend the basic shift-reduce transitions in different ways.
Here, crossing edges can be added with a transition that forms edges between the front of the buffer and a word anywhere in the stack, while the UCCA parser used swapping and a additional reduce actions for graph edges.
The models are similar, both using a form of stack-RNN, but with different structures (partly as a result of the different transition schemes).
The results in this case are not state-of-the-art, though this task has received more attention, and the data is slightly biased (the parser that does better, ACE, is based on the grammar that was used to determine which sentences to include).
However, the system can also be applied to AMR, and does fairly well, better than other neural AMR parsers at the time (and more recent ideas for improvements are large orthogonal).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-1112&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{buys-blunsom:2017:Long,
  author    = {Buys, Jan  and  Blunsom, Phil},
  title     = {Robust Incremental Neural Semantic Graph Parsing},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers)},
  month     = {July},
  year      = {2017},
  address   = {Vancouver, Canada},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {1215--1226},
  url       = {http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-1112}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search-based Neural Structured Learning for Sequential Question Answering (Iyyer et al., ACL 2017)</title>
      <link>http://www.jkk.name/post/2017-10-10_seqqa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 13:43:36 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jkk.name/post/2017-10-10_seqqa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Semantic parsing datasets generally consist of (question, answer) pairs, where each pair is completely independent of the rest (one exception is ATIS, which has multi-turn conversations, though most work doesn&amp;rsquo;t use them).
In reality, we often ask a series of simple questions that together form a complex one, for example &amp;ldquo;What flights are available from Detroit to Sydney? And how much is the price if I don&amp;rsquo;t want to leave before 8am?&amp;rdquo;
This work explores these kinds of sequential questions with a new dataset and algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dataset was formed by asking crowd workers to rephrase questions from the WikiTableQuestions dataset into sequences of shorter questions.
This naturally constrains the types of questions (in particular, they reference a single table only), but covers a range of domains.
With 6,066 question sequences, and on average 2.9 questions / sequence, it&amp;rsquo;s a large dataset by semantic parsing standards.
However, there are no logical forms, only the row, column, or cell(s) that contain the answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve the problem, they treat it as choosing a sequence of actions, where each action generate a part of the execution instructions.
The model follows the recent approach of considering the contents of the database as part of the calculation (e.g. by taking the dot product of the vector for a cell and the vector for the question).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system has consistently better performance than other QA systems on the new dataset (though no results are shown for the WikiTableQuestions dataset).
At only 12.8% of sequences completely correct, there is plenty of scope for improvement.
Based on the description of the operators there are definitely additional abilities that would be useful, so this model has potential to improve.
That said, it seems difficult to generalise the model to handle more complicated databases with multiple interconnected tables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://aclweb.org/anthology/P/P17/P17-1167.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{iyyer-yih-chang:2017:Long,
  author    = {Iyyer, Mohit  and  Yih, Wen-tau  and  Chang, Ming-Wei},
  title     = {Search-based Neural Structured Learning for Sequential Question Answering},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers)},
  month     = {July},
  year      = {2017},
  address   = {Vancouver, Canada},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {1821--1831},
  url       = {http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-1167}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Semantic Parsing with Semi-Supervised Sequential Autoencoders (Kocisky et al., EMNLP 2016)</title>
      <link>http://www.jkk.name/post/2017-10-09_parsing-autoencoder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 14:31:24 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jkk.name/post/2017-10-09_parsing-autoencoder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Semantic parsing datasets are small because they are expensive to produce (logical forms don&amp;rsquo;t occur naturally and writing them down takes time).
The idea here is to do semi-supervised learning by implementing both a parser and a generator, which are trained together as a form of autoencoder where the intermediate representation is natural language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The architecture has four LSTMs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bidirectional LSTM over a logical form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One directional LSTM attending to the first LSTM&amp;rsquo;s hidden states, generating a sentence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bidirectional LSTM over the sentence generated by the second LSTM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One directional LSTM attending to the third LSTM&amp;rsquo;s hidden states, generating a logical form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually a component like the second LSTM would choose the max word at each position (or use beam search), but here they want this whole thing to be differentiable, so the distribution over words is used.
At evaluation time only the second half (3+4) is used, with the test sentence as input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this structure, a loss function is defined that compares the input to (1) and the output of (4), which in both cases is a logical form.
As a result, they don&amp;rsquo;t need (logical form, sentence) pairs to train, they can use automatically generated logical forms.
Of course, with only logical forms it would do something random with the intermediate representation, so some supervised examples are also needed (in which case the two halves are trained independently).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results are not state-of-the-art, but good on all three tasks (Geoquery, NLmaps, SAIL), and on two they show am improvement over training (3+4) with only supervised data.
Varying the amount of training data gives a less clear picture.
On Geoquery with 5-25% of the data, this approach clearly helps, particularly if the queries are real rather than generated (which is a realistic scenario), but then there is no improvement for 50% or 75%, and at 100% the improvement is small.
On NLmaps there was no generator, and the differences at different data %s seem like noise.
SAIL has the most clear benefit, though it&amp;rsquo;s a particularly small dataset, consisting of paths in just four maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a cool idea that seems effective in certain situations.
The generator is key, and it&amp;rsquo;s possible that performance on GeoQuery would be higher with a more sophisticated one (e.g. a tree structured generator, rather than the ngram model used here).
One idea mentioned in the conclusion is to try reversing the setup (3-4-1-2) and training with natural language examples that have no logical form.
How to tradeoff the different data scenarios seems like an interesting challenge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://aclweb.org/anthology/D16-1116&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{kovcisky-EtAl:2016:EMNLP2016,
  author    = {Ko\v{c}isk\&#39;{y}, Tom\&#39;{a}\v{s}  and  Melis, G\&#39;{a}bor  and  Grefenstette, Edward  and  Dyer, Chris  and  Ling, Wang  and  Blunsom, Phil  and  Hermann, Karl Moritz},
  title     = {Semantic Parsing with Semi-Supervised Sequential Autoencoders},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing},
  month     = {November},
  year      = {2016},
  address   = {Austin, Texas},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {1078--1087},
  url       = {https://aclweb.org/anthology/D16-1116}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
