<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>word-vectors | Jonathan K. Kummerfeld</title>
    <link>http://www.jkk.name/tag/word-vectors/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://www.jkk.name/tag/word-vectors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>word-vectors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Jonathan K. Kummerfeld</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 21:09:58 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://www.jkk.name/images/icon_hua0d6326cebee282657b97e45398e76a5_17367_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>word-vectors</title>
      <link>http://www.jkk.name/tag/word-vectors/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning the Curriculum with Bayesian Optimization for Task-Specific Word Representation Learning (Tsvetkov et al., 2016)</title>
      <link>http://www.jkk.name/post/2018-03-05_curriculum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 21:09:58 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jkk.name/post/2018-03-05_curriculum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Usually when we learn, we have a curriculum designed to incrementally build understanding.
It seems reasonable that the same idea could be useful for machine learning, and indeed there is a large body of work on the topic.
This paper explores the specific question of whether a curriculum can help develop task-specific word vectors, and whether we can determine an effective curriculum automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They define a linear model with a range of features that characterise a paragraph of text, such as the number of distinct words, the number of prepositional phrases, and the average number of syllables per word.
Paragraphs are sorted by the model and used to train word vectors with word2vec.
These word vectors are then used as part of a model for a target task, giving a score that indicates the quality of the curriculum.
Based on this score the weights for the model are updated, using a form of Bayesian optimisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One really nice aspect of this paper is the range of tasks considered: sentiment analysis, NER, POS tagging, and parsing.
Learning a curriculum does improve performance slightly, and which features are important varies across the tasks (indicating the importance of task-specific curriculums).
However, the models are somewhat restricted (as shown by the low absolute performance) because they do not change the word vectors during training.
For most of this paper that&amp;rsquo;s a reasonable decision, as it allows a clearer learning signal, but it would have been interesting to also see the impact on the normal training scenario and a state-of-the-art model.
In my experience (and in our soon-to-appear NAACL paper) we find that variations in word vectors can disappear during training for a downstream task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/P16-1013&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{tsvetkov-EtAl:2016:P16-1,
  author    = {Tsvetkov, Yulia  and  Faruqui, Manaal  and  Ling, Wang  and  MacWhinney, Brian  and  Dyer, Chris},
  title     = {Learning the Curriculum with Bayesian Optimization for Task-Specific Word Representation Learning},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers)},
  month     = {August},
  year      = {2016},
  address   = {Berlin, Germany},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {130--139},
  url       = {http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/P16-1013}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Regularization-based Algorithm for Learning Cross-Domain Word Embeddings (Yang et al., 2017)</title>
      <link>http://www.jkk.name/post/2017-12-12_multidomainwordvector/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 20:25:40 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jkk.name/post/2017-12-12_multidomainwordvector/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To construct word vectors from multi-domain data, use a separate vector for each domain and add a loss term to encourage them to agree.
Here the loss is an l2 norm, weighted by a factor that depends on the frequency of the words in the two domains.
The factor is the harmonic mean of the normalised frequency in each domain (so the lower frequency dominates the factor, pulling it lower).
Across a range of tasks this consistently performs better than other approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aclweb.org/anthology/D17-1312&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{yang-lu-zheng:2017:EMNLP2017,
  author    = {Yang, Wei  and  Lu, Wei  and  Zheng, Vincent},
  title     = {A Simple Regularization-based Algorithm for Learning Cross-Domain Word Embeddings},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 2017 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing},
  month     = {September},
  year      = {2017},
  address   = {Copenhagen, Denmark},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {2898--2904},
  url       = {https://www.aclweb.org/anthology/D17-1312}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The strange geometry of skip-gram with negative sampling (Mimno et al., 2017)</title>
      <link>http://www.jkk.name/post/2017-12-12_wordvectorgeometry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 20:15:34 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jkk.name/post/2017-12-12_wordvectorgeometry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It turns out that if the vectors learned by word2vec are projected into a plane they all point in the same direction.
Also, the context vectors (which are part of the algorithm, but not retained afterwards) point the other way.
When visualising with t-SNE this effect is not visible because of the way the space is warped to optimise the t-SNE objective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is surprising, and may seem problematic since it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit our goals for what these vectors should be capturing.
However, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to impact downstream tasks, for example, GloVe does not have this property, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to derive a great benefit from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aclweb.org/anthology/D17-1308&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{mimno-thompson:2017:EMNLP2017,
  author    = {Mimno, David  and  Thompson, Laure},
  title     = {The strange geometry of skip-gram with negative sampling},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 2017 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing},
  month     = {September},
  year      = {2017},
  address   = {Copenhagen, Denmark},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {2873--2878},
  url       = {https://www.aclweb.org/anthology/D17-1308}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPINE: SParse Interpretable Neural Embeddings (Subramanian et al., 2017)</title>
      <link>http://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-28_interpretableembeddings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 16:51:09 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-28_interpretableembeddings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first step in almost any neural network model for language is to look up a vector for each token in the input.
These vectors express relations between the words, but it is difficult to know exactly what relations.
This work proposes a way to modify a vector space of words to have more interpretable dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core idea is actually more general, it is a new loss that encourages sparsity in an auto-encoder.
In this case the model is very simple: input a word vector, apply an affine transformation and a pointwise nonlinearity, producing a hidden vector, then apply another affine transformation to get the output.
The loss is a combination of how well the input and output match (reconstruction loss), plus a function that is minimised when the average activation is below a threshold (average sparsity loss), and the new idea, a loss that is minimised at either 0 or 1 for each hidden value.
To get the hidden values to be bounded between 1 and 0, the nonlinearity used is a modified ReLU that stops increasing after reaching 1.
After training, the hidden values become the new word vectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To evaluate interpretability they consider the top 4 words along each dimension, add a random word, and ask a person to identify the odd word out.
Using either word2vec or GloVe as the initial vectors and applying this method, the results shown a dramatic difference (~25 vs. ~70).
On downstream tasks the story is more mixed.
With 1,000 dimensional vectors, there is usually an improvement for GloVe, but not for word2vec, and the differences are generally small.
Apparently going up to 2,000 further improves interpretability scores, but &amp;lsquo;at a severe cost&amp;rsquo; for the downstream tasks.
Going the other direction, to 500, hurts interpretability, and probably doesn&amp;rsquo;t improve downstream performance (it isn&amp;rsquo;t mentioned).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would be curious to see if taking these new word vectors and applying them to a downstream task like parsing, but letting them change during training, would be beneficial.
The general idea of a sparse auto-encoder also seems cool and may have other applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1711.08792&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ArXiv Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@ARTICLE{2017arXiv171108792S,
  author        = {{Subramanian}, A. and {Pruthi}, D. and {Jhamtani}, H. and {Berg-Kirkpatrick}, T. and {Hovy}, E.},
  title         = {SPINE: SParse Interpretable Neural Embeddings},
  journal       = {ArXiv e-prints},
  archivePrefix = {arXiv},
  eprint        = {1711.08792},
  primaryClass  = {cs.CL},
  year          = {2017},
  month         = {November},
  url           = {https://arxiv.org/abs/1711.08792},
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Distributed Representations of Texts and Entities from Knowledge Base (Yamada et al., 2017)</title>
      <link>http://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-15_entityvectors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 18:01:27 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jkk.name/post/2017-11-15_entityvectors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since word2vec was released there have been a series of X2vec papers, though none have had the success of word vectors.
In this case the idea is to represent entities and chunks of text (words, sentences, paragraphs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entities are represented with vectors.
To get the vector for a chunk of text, they:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sum word vectors for the text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rescale to be of unit length.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiply by a weight matrix and add a bias.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then to learn these, negative log likelihood is used, where the probability is defined as a softmax over the dot product between entity and text vectors.
The data is a portion of Wikipedia annotated with entities as indicated by links (plus they say the entity the page is about is implicitly part of every sentence).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these new vectors in hand, they try textual similarity, with strong results.
They also build a very simple entity linking system, a feed-forward network with these representations plus a few other features, and beat all prior work.
Similarly
They apply the same modeling approach to Quizball QA, also with strong results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simplicity and effectiveness of the model really is impressive.
Some qualitative examples are included, but hard to find trends in.
It does seem like a more reasonable vector learning approach than skip-thought and other similar approaches that rely only on text context - the entities provide something different, but clearly closely related.
That said, I feel like more ablation is needed to see what role each of these pieces is playing (are they learning better vectors, or using them in a way that is more effective? Or both?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.transacl.org/ojs/index.php/tacl/article/view/1065&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@article{TACL1065,
	author = {Yamada, Ikuya  and Shindo, Hiroyuki  and Takeda, Hideaki  and Takefuji, Yoshiyasu },
	title = {Learning Distributed Representations of Texts and Entities from Knowledge Base},
	journal = {Transactions of the Association for Computational Linguistics},
	volume = {5},
	year = {2017},
	issn = {2307-387X},
	url = {https://www.transacl.org/ojs/index.php/tacl/article/view/1065},
	pages = {397--411}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal Word Distributions (Athiwaratkun and Wilson, 2017)</title>
      <link>http://www.jkk.name/post/2017-10-26_multimodalwordembeddings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 20:47:12 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jkk.name/post/2017-10-26_multimodalwordembeddings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Word2Vec and other approaches provide a single vector representing a word&amp;rsquo;s meaning, giving words spatially defined relationships capturing relatedness.
A natural extension is to consider regions in that space and allow some words to take up larger or smaller regions.
Another natural idea is to allow a single word to have multiple representations, to capture the different senses.
This paper considers both of those ideas, using multiple gaussian distributions per word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using gaussians has the nice property that there is a closed form for calculating the amount of overlap between them, which is used as a measure of similarity.
Following ideas from word2vec, during learning the aim is to increase similarity between words that occur together and decrease it between random pairs that do not occur together.
Once the word representations are learned, KL divergence is used for similarity, along with the standard approaches that only look at the gaussian centres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In practise, two spherical distributions per word is sufficient.
Performance is better than word2vec and several other approaches for multi-sense word embeddings.
There was one puzzling line about the model suffering larger variance problems, but it was not quantified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be very interesting to inject some knowledge, such as from WordNet, to guide the number of gaussians per word, rather than giving them all N.
The paper also doesn&amp;rsquo;t get into details about the learned space, for example, are the two senses often far apart or close together? (in the latter case it is learning a slightly non-linear spatial representation).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-1151&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{athiwaratkun-wilson:2017:Long,
  author    = {Athiwaratkun, Ben  and  Wilson, Andrew},
  title     = {Multimodal Word Distributions},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers)},
  month     = {July},
  year      = {2017},
  address   = {Vancouver, Canada},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {1645--1656},
  url       = {http://aclweb.org/anthology/P17-1151}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Factored Neural Network Model for Characterizing Online Discussions in Vector Space (Cheng et al., EMNLP 2017)</title>
      <link>http://www.jkk.name/post/2017-10-16_forumrnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 20:55:07 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.jkk.name/post/2017-10-16_forumrnn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Attention - a weighted average over a set of vectors representing context - has consistently produced positive results.
Here we see an example of how it can be applied in the case of modeling a threaded discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attention is applied in two ways.
First, over a fixed set of vectors.
This is intended to provide a mechanism to choose between several different sub-models contained within a single model.
Put differently, the vectors provide a set of latent representations that capture each of the different types of posts in the subreddit.
Second, attention over the current utterance is used in the process of predicting responses (at training time only).
This provides an additional source of input to the model, by forcing it to explain the response utterances using the same representations as a source of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application is a new task, using values assigned to posts = upvotes - downvotes (i.e. Reddit karma).
Predicting the specific value is hard, so the task is split into 7 binary decisions about whether a post has a score higher or lower than some value.
On this task the new approach provides consistent gains, though overall performance remains low (53 - 56%).
Confusingly though, one of the figures (number 4) seems to suggest that it was a single multi-way decision, not a set of binary decisions.
I&amp;rsquo;m also curious about the data, in particular what the distribution of scores is.
The paper mentions it is Zipfian, but surely it would be something double-sided with a massive peak at 0 and a rapid drop in either direction?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, this is further evidence of the versatility of the idea of attention!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://aclweb.org/anthology/D17-1242.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@InProceedings{cheng-fang-ostendorf:2017:EMNLP2017,
  author    = {Cheng, Hao  and  Fang, Hao  and  Ostendorf, Mari},
  title     = {A Factored Neural Network Model for Characterizing Online Discussions in Vector Space},
  booktitle = {Proceedings of the 2017 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing},
  month     = {September},
  year      = {2017},
  address   = {Copenhagen, Denmark},
  publisher = {Association for Computational Linguistics},
  pages     = {2286--2296},
  url       = {https://www.aclweb.org/anthology/D17-1242}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
